James Smith

Senior Full Stack Developer

Website: https://webdevych.github.io/
Gmail: lee.smith870327@gmail.com
GitHub: https://github.com/WebDevYCH/

OVERVIEW

A highly skilled web developer who is comfortable with both front-end and back-end programming.

I've been working as a web developer for 7 years and built many professional experiences on web development with several companies and clients satisfying them 100%.

Strong organizational and project management skills, good problem-solving skills, attention to detail, and excellent verbal communication skills are my specific features.

SKILLS

• Front-end:

React / Next, Vue / Nuxt HTML, CSS, Tailwind CSS JavaScript / jQuery, Bootstrap

Back-end:

PHP / Laravel / Symfony / Yii Node.js / Express.js Python / Django

Mobile:

Java, Flutter, React Native

• Databases:

MySQL / MongoDB / PostgreSQL

• Payment Process:

PayPal / Stripe / Google payment

• Cloud Services:

AWS (Lambda, EC2, S3) / Firebase (Firestore, Real-time Database)

Other:

Heroku / GoDaddy / Docker / Webpack, GitHub

EXPERIENCE

Frontend Developer (React/Next) | Ronday | Full-Time | Remote

Aug 2021 – Jun 2022

- Built and deployed a pattern-library for the Ronday UI using storybook, semantic HTML elements and CSS
- Developed a reusable template based on pattern-library using React, Next.js
- Developed Ronday website and admin site based on templates
- Tested website using jest, testing framework and Cypress, Selenium for end-to-end testing.
- Integrated Auth0, Amazon Cognito for authentication.
- Collaborated backend team to interact API calls.

Skills: React, Next.js, Redux toolkit, Tailwind CSS, Storybook, JavaScript, Typescript

Senior Full Stack Developer | Inmetrics | Full-Time | Remote

Jul 2019 - Dec 2019

- Implemented new responsive, mobile-first approach which increased mobile traffic by 30%.
- Implemented websites, mobile applications, and landing pages from concept through deployment.
- Standardized all output with a new, responsive, mobile-first approach and strategy.
- Assessed UX and UI designs for technical feasibility.
- Developed standard and ad hoc reports in graph format as required.

Skills: React.js, Next.js, TypeScript, Node.js, Express.js, React Native

Python Developer | Straits Interactive | Full-Time | Remote

Apr 2018 - Nov 2018

- Oversaw full lifecycle of software development for 5 projects with 100% on time delivery while staying 5% under budget.
- Designed processes for cleanup and performance improvement that minimized downtime by 9%.
- Assisted the design team by delivering pixel-perfect implementation of websites for over +7 projects.
- Introduced new technologies into the company's production team by resulting 15% increase sales.

Skills: Python, Django, JavaScript, React

EDUCATION

The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology

Master's degree on Computer Science